# SAYO EVERDEN

SavoEverden@gmail.com

+1 (250) 718-2389



github.com/sayo96825



sayo96825.github.io/



www.linkedin.com/in/SayoEverden



A recent graduate from UBC with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science with 10+ years of customer service and management experience.

I have just completed the UBC Data Science certificate and Google data analytics professional certificate and I am looking for an opportunity to start, grow and contribute to the field of information technology.

### CERTIFICATION

#### **UBC**

- Key Capabilities in Data Science

## Google

- Data Analytics Professional Certificate

## **AWARDS**

- ★ U.S Presidential Award for **Community Service**
- **★** Undergraduate Scholarship to **UBC Vancouver**

#### LANGUAGE

**English** 

**Japanese** 

# **SKILLS**

- Data Analytics including Python, R and SQL
- Leadership, Multitasking/Organization, Problem Solving, Data Analysis, Presentation, Public Speaking, Communication, Time Management and Risk Assessment skills with 10+ years of family business and restaurant management experience
- SQL including MySQL, MSSQL and PostgreSQL
- Data Visualization such as Tableau, Altair, Ggplot, Matplotlib, SciPy and
- Data Modeling, Data Collection, Data Wrangling/Mungling, Machine Learning, Data Mining and Social Media Analysis

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Computer Science:

University of British Columbia Okanagan, Kelowna 2022

Bachelor of Psychology:

2008 University of British Columbia Okanagan, Kelowna

Associate of Art with Honor

2003 TransPacific Hawaii College

# **PROJECT**

Capstone Project: LIMS (Laboratory Information Management System) Led the team of 4 as a **project manager** to develop the LIMS system **from** ground up for an actual client who was new to software development by continuously adapting to the change due to the tremendous gap in scope and limitations of the capstone project.

Direct Study: Social Computing

Proposed a two-phase project on ageism during the covid pandemic. Using the data analysis research finding from the first phase, I developed a **social media website** called "Boomer "Millenials" to facilitate the interaction among generations to close the generation gap.

Social Media Data Analysis Research

Conducted **social media data analysis research** on Autism Spectrum disorder and social media use.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

- Everden Rust Funeral Service Kelowna, BC

2010 - 2020

Office Assistant / Business Analyst

Proposed to open a third location in Westside, BC. Our funeral home has grown from 5 employees with two locations to 10 employees with three locations.

- Restaurant Management /Software Implementation

Implemented a restaurant management software system (Vancouver POS) into five restaurants collaborating with people with more than a dozen nationalities and unique backgrounds.

Ozeki Kelowna, BC 2006 - current Dozo Kelowna, BC 2017 - 2020 Osho Winfield, BC 2019 Basil Leaf 2018 - current

Kelowna. BC Glenmore Highway97 Kelowna. BC Peachland Peachland, BC

2022 Mini-Ozeki Kelowna, BC